PHONE RINGS
Murder Investigation Team. PS Jatri.
Received. Stand by.
Fields.
Chris.
SIREN WAILS
Sorry to ruin your evening. boss.
We just had a call
from a Chis Handler
submitting information relevant
to Vella.
What did they say?
Possible suspect - a person.
so far unknown to the inquiry.
alleged to have made a confession.
Intel's graded
the info 1A on the matrix.
OK. continue developing the intel.
Let's bring the suspect in.
Nice one. Right on it. boss.
Five three.
the boss has given the go-ahead.
Sorry to call you in. sir.
Right. any progress since we spoke
on the phone?
We've a possible
location for the suspect.
You OK to sign off the
Directed Surveillance Authority?
I need a team on watch
while we pull everything together
to raid the premises.
How reliable's the intel?
1A from an established Chis.
Casual sex worker.
He supplied the suspect's address...
Hold on. Jo. A rent boy?
I don't know if it's a commercial
thing with the Chis.
or even what his drugs history is.
Christ sake. Jo.
he was probably off his face.
Look. just let me
get a coffee inside me first.
This is our first lead in months.
Bloody hell. Jo.
We good to go. boss?
Sorry. Chris. the Super's not buying
the intel.
What?
He needs more time.
God's sake.
Stand down. guys.
It's not happening.
Super's pulling the plug.
Says he wants more work up
on the intel.
Morning. Morning. boss. Ma'am.
And don't think I didn't notice
DI Fleming skulking in last-minute
like the dirty stop-out.
Don't go there. boss - glass houses.
All right. Operation Lighthouse
re the unsolved murder of Gail Vella
on September 10th. 2019.
Apologies to those of you who were
gearing up for the op last night.
Following the Super's conflab
with the SFC.
it was decided to await
Executive Level sign-off.
The name we've been given
is Ross Turner.
Yesterday evening. Turner allegedly
boasted to a Chis
he'd been involved in Gail's murder.
Turner's name is negative on the PNC
and the National Database.
plus local intel checks
are drawing blanks.
Hence. we're treating "Ross Turner"
as most likely an alias.
We've been given an address -
Flat 4F. Beechwood House.
In-situ surveillance
was established last night.
The team captured this image.
Enhanced here.
Turner is likely to be armed and is
considered extremely dangerous.
Tickets ready. please.
Here you are. There you go.
There you go.
Tango Oscar six five. TL the Hill.
Control. received. six five.
Mike India two zero. state five.
Mike India. control received.
Did anyone see that?
What? Take us round the back.
What did you see. boss?
Take us round.
Mike India two zero. control.
re-routing state five
to possible armed robbery.
Control. two zero received.
standing by for sit rep.
Boss. maybe we should just
call it in?
What the hell?
Stop at the end. no further.
See. Kate - the van.
Mike India. control. Mike India
three seven. vehicle PNC check.
Control. three seven. go ahead.
Three seven.
Sierra. hotel. one. three.
golf. echo. kilo.
God's sake.
What the hell are they playing at?
Control. three seven. vehicle is
a red BMW 3-series. no markers.
Vehicle comes back to
a Helen Braxted. 59 Lowman Avenue.
Three seven. received.
Let's call in backup so we can TL.
It's only a fake plate. boss.
You know a getaway vehicle
when you see one. Kate.
Bookies right there.
Can't rule out an immediate
risk to the public.
Mike India two zero to TFC. believed
state six at armed robbery.
request urgent authorisation
to deploy.
Mike India control. clear to deploy.
Mike India two zero. deploy.
Two zero. received.
Mike India two zero. go. six five.
Mike India two zero.
intercept vehicle.
Two zero. received.
Armed police!
Armed police! Hands on the window!
Out of the vehicle now!
Down on your knees.
Armed police! Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapons!
Armed Police. Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapon!
Shit. shit. shit!
Control. three seven.
active message - shot fired.
request urgent ambulance.
One non-police casualty. severe GSW.
Move them back. Clear the street.
I need replacement AFOs urgently
to continue operation
to arrest Vella suspect.
Repeat. urgently.
Control. received. stand by.
Get down. Don't move.
Shit!
Six five. unarmed clear to approach.
Two zero. received.
Let's secure the scene and witnesses
and get this lot back to The Hill.
Ma'am. Take witness details and
record a first account.
You OK to stay here and take charge
while I lead the arrest
of the Vella suspect?
Yeah. no problem. ma'am.
Hold him. Jesus.
One. two. three... Take them off!
Officers wearing body cams. get in
here now
and start making arrests.
Control. Mike India two zero.
priority message.
Two zero.
Control. two zero.
following firearms incident.
AFOs must stand down
for forensic recovery.
Deployment of relief
AFOs will be at least one hour.
Shit!
Two zero. control. anything to speed
that up would be deeply appreciated.
Six five. all AFOs remain in situ
for forensic recovery.
Six five. received.
Sorry. Sarge. We've made a request
for Officer K
to provide receipts or equivalent
supporting his expenses claims.
It's been ten working days
and we've got nothing.
Call the rep and say
unless they deliver.
we're moving to a yellow notice.
Will do. Officer S. she's been
calling in sick.
but colleagues allege she's been
skiving off to help run her
husband's haulage business.
I suppose we'd better start
by asking occ health
to request a doctor's letter. Sarge.
Five three. relief ARVs are TA.
All yours. Kate. Boss.
Two zero. received.
Everybody. let's go.
Christ. How much time
did that cost us?
Too much.
Two zero state five.
TA minus one minute.
Control. received.
Mike India two zero. Sierra Lima one
five. request sit rep.
Sierra Lima one five. receiving.
No change. Subject believed still
in property.
Two zero. received.
Mike India two zero. control.
TA Beechwood House.
Control. two zero. received.
Mike India two zero. state six.
Sierra Lima one five.
visual with ARVs.
Two zero six nine. no further intel.
Suspect is believed to be armed
and dangerous.
Six nine. received.
Two zero six nine.
ambulance now on standby.
Over to you.
Zero foxtrot six nine. received.
We're go.
Six nine. going up.
Control. six nine. received.
One five.
no movement seen in Flat 4F.
Six nine. received.
Two zero. forensics now TA.
Control. two zero. received.
Six nine. fourth Floor.
Control. six nine. received.
One five.
Still no obs on subject's dwelling.
It's your call.
Two zero. received.
Enter the property.
Received.
Weapons free.
Armed police!
Armed police! Show yourself!
Armed police! Hands where
we can see them!
One five.
they're in but still no obs.
Two zero. received.
awaiting sit rep.
Mike India two zero.
require urgent sit rep.
One five. still no obs.
Sierra foxtrot six nine.
all officers secure.
One in custody.
Control. six nine. received.
With me. let's go.
Two zero. request FC go back-to-back
on two.
FC on two.
They're holding
the suspect at the scene.
I need you to go up there
and get him
straight into a forensic
suit for transport to a dry cell.
Every fibre. every strand
of DNA could be crucial
in proving this is our guy.
FC. received.
Chris. do me a favour.
put on a suit and get up there. pal.
Boss.
Six nine. forensics clear to enter.
Five three. state six.
Received. five three.
Five three. DP for custody transfer.
Bringing suspect out now.
Control. five three. received.
Thanks for stepping in.
Totally fantastic work.
Happy to help. ma'am.
Ident one was a negative
on his prints.
At first. he was reluctant
to give a name.
and then he did confirm Ross Turner.
Sorry. Chris.
did he volunteer the name
or was he asked a leading question
if Ross Turner was his name?
Good point. Kate.
The name was put to him first.
The Chis's... The ID for the...
Sorry. boss. great minds.
So. the Chis who gave us
Turner's name and address -
we need to get him in to confirm or
deny ID on the suspect.
I've been on it all day. ma'am.
Handler's lost contact.
He reckons the Chis has bottled it.
Christ sake.
Sorry. Chris.
maybe have one more go. please?
Boss.
Clearly Turner's not
what we expected.
if that's even his name.
Custody's asked the HCP to carry out
an initial mental state examination
to make sure he's got the capacity
to face an interview.
Not just an interview.
A person with learning difficulties
is more likely to be the victim
of crime than the perpetrator.
You wonder if he's got the capacity
to carry out a murder
in the first place.
There's always been two theories.
One - a hit.
I agree. Kate. he's not our man.
Two - a stalker slash obsessed fan.
That's by far the more
credible theory.
All right. I'll get right back
to you.
Sarge. front desk called up.
There's an officer asking for you.
Won't say what about.
Won't even give a name.
It's late.
Fine. I'll deal with
it on my way out.
Steve Arnott. Farida?
I'd rather not give my name.
I can appreciate why that might be
but. sorry.
if you're still at Polk Avenue.
AC-3 have jurisdiction now
and you should contact them.
I'm on the Hill.
Murder Investigation Team.
Wait there.
Can I get you a tea or coffee
or anything?
No. thanks.
The rate of unsolved crimes is
proving to be a nightmare.
But it helps the public to realise
that we don't have the resources
to investigate burglaries.
With any luck. they'll stop
reporting them.
the figures will look better.
Ted. Ma'am.
Ted. Ted.
Apologies. ma'am. I just saw you
booked the conference room there.
My office must have cocked up.
I never got the invitation.
No cock-up.
Sorry. Ted.
you're not on the list this time.
I accepted the
disciplinary action. ma'am.
This matter is now closed.
You lead an anti-corruption unit.
There's plenty think you're lucky
not to have been removed.
Best keep your head down. Ted.
Got a few minutes. gaffer?
Be my guest. son. Be my guest.
Last night. I took
a statement from Officer J
who was working
at Polk Avenue in 2017
when we investigated
DCI Roz Huntley. Mm.
Now. Officer J expressed concerns
regarding the professional conduct
of DCI Joanne Davidson.
an SIO on the Murder Investigation
Team based at Hillside Lane.
Hillside Lane. yeah. everybody's
talking about this breakthrough
they've made - a suspect in custody
for Vella.
Yes. sir. DCI Davidson was posted
to the Hill a year ago.
one month after Gail Vella's murder.
She took over from the original SIO
leading the inquiry.
As you know. sir. Gail Vella drove
home late
on the evening of September 10th in
a dark grey Peugeot 108.
which she parked outside her house
in Kingsgate.
and was shot dead as she got out of
the vehicle.
At postmortem. the pathologist
concluded the muzzle of the firearm
had been pressed against the back of
the skull
at the moment of discharge.
Hard-contact technique
to minimise the spread of sound.
powder and blood.
According to Officer J. the suspect
appears to lack the capacity
to carry out a murder that's still
unsolved after over a year.
She also alleges DCI Davidson
unnecessarily diverted
and delayed the operation
to arrest the suspect.
And any previous
criticism of Davidson on record?
None I've found so far. sir.
I'd like to covertly approach
current members of her team.
Wee Chloe. she seems to be
getting on really well out there.
doesn't she? What do you say. son?
She's good. sir.
We really can't be sure about
the loyalty of some of these people.
They could banjax the whole thing.
Sir. regardless of
the personnel involved.
Vella's still the highest-profile
inquiry engaging this force.
And Officer J didn't go to AC-3
or AC-9.
She came to AC-12 because
she believes we'll do right by her.
Well. she backed the right horse
there. didn't she. son?
But I'm going to need a hell of
a lot more
before I can authorise
a formal inquiry.
Sir... Houl yer whisht.
I need more.
Sir.
All right? Hey.
It's great to see you. You too.
I got you one. Hope that's
OK. I'm on the clock.
No. great. I appreciate you making
the time.
I should be calling you "ma'am".
Strictly speaking.
but I'll let you off.
So. how can I help you. Steve?
Strictly off the record.
I've reached the end of the line
in anti-corruption.
About time.
It's no disrespect to the gaffer.
I've stuck it out.
but I'm bored. mate.
I'm ready for a new challenge.
Well. we can always use good people.
Cheers. I appreciate it.
Sorry. um. I should get back.
But maybe do a drink one night?
Um...
Luke and I have split up.
No. it's just...if we're going
to be working together...
You really have been working
anti-corruption too long. ain't you?
Good to see you.
DI Fleming. MIT.
Thanks. Ma'am.
A number of newspaper
and magazine clippings
containing images of Gail Vella.
Morning. Kate.
Boss. All right. Chris.
All right. ma'am.
I was just saying there's a number
of newspaper and magazine cuttings
containing images of Gail Vella.
Significant.
Abundant fingerprints
and DNA deposits.
And the prints appear to relate
to two individuals only -
one of who is the suspect we've got
in custody.
OK.
The search team detected
signs of forced entry.
Our AFOs smashed the front door in.
The damage is on the inside
of the door.
The markings match the damage
to the back of this chair.
Any estimate on when this alleged
forced entry happened?
No.
It's Farida. OK if I take this?
Sure.
Hi. Farida...
Possibly the chair was jammed
up against the front door
to prevent someone breaking in.
Like Chris said.
that could have happened any time.
Well. the place is well maintained.
It's unlikely the damage would have
gone unrepaired for long.
Unlikely but not impossible.
Good news. HCP's OK'd the
suspect for interview.
Great.
Have a seat.
We'll be with you the whole time.
and if you get confused by anything.
it's OK to tell us.
TAPE RECORDER BUZZES
That's just the tape recorder
starting. It won't last long.
Murder Investigation Team
interview of suspect A
by Detective Chief
Inspector Davidson
and Detective Sergeant Lomax
in the presence of the suspect's
solicitor and appropriate adult.
You do not have to say anything.
It may harm your defence
if you do not mention.
when questioned. something you later
rely on in court.
Anything you do say may be
used in evidence.
Do you understand?
Yes.
What's your name?
If I may?
My client's informed me that under
the strain of initial questioning.
he gave the name Ross Turner.
His name is not Ross Turner.
His name is Terry Boyle.
Is that your name. then -
Terry Boyle?
For the DIR. the suspect is nodding.
Why did you say your name
was Ross Turner?
My client's been clear.
His name is not Ross Turner.
His name is Terry Boyle.
OK. We'll look into that.
Moving on.
The property where
you were arrested -
Flat 4F. Beechwood House -
is that where you live?
Do you live in the property or
were you just visiting?
No.
No. you don't live there or no.
you weren't visiting?
Mr Boyle has provided me
with his address.
He does not reside
at Beechwood House.
He resides in the Kingsgate area -
Flat B. Dorton Villas.
OK. we'll look into that as well.
Interestingly. the Kingsgate area is
where a journalist
called Gail Vella lived.
Do you know who I'm talking about?
Suspect nodded.
Thank you.
For the DIR. I'm showing the suspect
item reference RCG-6.
RCG-6 is a press cutting featuring
an image of Gail Vella.
I'm also showing the suspect item
reference RCG-7.
another press cutting featuring
an image of Gail Vella.
and item reference RCG-8.
also a press cutting featuring
an image of Gail Vella.
Do you recognise
these press cuttings?
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
Do you recognise this woman?
For the DIR. the suspect is nodding.
What's your relationship
to this woman?
Nice lady.
Suspect answered. "nice lady."
MIT have put the IDs of the
armed robbers up on the database.
Have a look at this.
This it?
Exactly. Between them. these guys
have never robbed anything bigger
than their local Greggs.
And they just happened to be on
the exact route at the time of an op
to bring in a suspect
in an unsolved murder.
Based on Officer J's statement. the
MIT convoy was travelling uphill.
past this parade of shops.
Well. where's the bookies?
It's around the corner.
It's already a narrow line of sight.
You add in Davidson's convoy
travelling at high speed.
I'll call in for the footage
off the security camera.
You go and check out the camera
in the bookies. Sarge.
DI Fleming. MIT. visiting Terry
Boyle's flat. Ma'am.
Thanks.
Hi. any updates?
So far. apart from the pics
on the walls.
we're not finding much evidence
of this being anyone's
permanent residence. let alone
the suspect's.
The place is clean.
Extremely clean.
Ta.
So. the suspect's alleged address
contained even more
Gail Vella images.
and neighbours positively
ID'd his picture.
Meanwhile. we've interviewed
a number of residents
at Beechwood House.
Whoever lived in Flat F kept
himself to himself.
and the few that did notice
a resident describe him
as dark-haired and stocky.
Like Terry Boyle.
What we really need is
the Chis to confirm
whether Terry Boyle was the man that
confessed to an involvement
in Gail Vella's murder.
or it was someone else entirely.
Tell me about it.
My patience is all used up.
Set up an urgent meet
with the Chis's handler.
Cheers. boss.
Boss. this is the Chis's handler.
I've brought him
up to speed on our inquiry.
DS Marks. DCI Davidson.
You'll have heard from Kate how
important it is
for us to acquire your Chis's intel.
I'm doing everything I can.
I don't know what more you expect.
For a start. you could help us
locate your Chis.
I've been trying to make contact
with him. He's gone to ground.
Then no disrespect. mate. but
we've got the resources to find him.
You're asking me
to disclose his identity?
You know I can't do that.
Is the word "ma'am"
in your vocabulary?
To locate your Chis and convey him
to a place of safety
from which he can assist
our inquiry.
we need you to disclose
his identity.
No.
Ma'am.
Are you worried about him?
Yes. Of course. I am.
I'm sorry. Sarge.
RINGING TONE
VOICEMAIL: You've reached
PS Farida Jatri.
Please leave a message.
Farida. it's Steve Arnott.
Look. we're progressing the inquiry.
but I need your help to fill
in some of the gaps.
Call me when you can. OK?
Thank you.
PHONE RINGS
MIT. DI Fleming.
Thanks for calling me back. Sarge.
How do you spell that?
Jo?
Sir?
The Chief Constable's been on.
I said I'd call back
with an update.
Too early to say. sir.
I should have been back home ages
ago. my feet up.
Have you got our man or not?
Like I said. sir. too early to say.
We'll need another 12 hours
with him.
Oh. for God's sake.
We've hit a bit
of a brick wall. sir.
The Chis. he's dropped off
the radar.
If this is going to go the way we
want. we need to find out who he is.
MUFFLED VOICES
We've got a job to do.
The handler's
within his rights not to.
Fuck the handler.
And fuck the Chis.
OK. Any chance you could scan over
the paperwork?
Suspect's been bedded down
for a rest period.
Not much more happening tonight.
I might leave soon.
I was thinking the same.
No worries. you've been a big help.
OK. Thanks. Bye.
Sorry. boss. What's up?
I've taken reports from
the surveillance teams in situ
at Beechwood House where
Terry Boyle was arrested.
When we were diverted to
the armed robbery.
there was some confusion over
the Surveillance Authority.
What confusion?
Well. the team was only in place
under Directed Authority.
and it got queried as requiring
Intrusive Authority
because they were using extreme
high-power lenses
to view inside the property.
DAVIDSON SIGHS
Shit.
Yeah. Which means they had to pull
out until it was sorted.
Looks like the Super messed
up the paperwork.
How long was Beechwood House not
under surveillance?
Three and a half hours.
Which means we don't know
if Terry Boyle is this person...
..or this person was able
to flee the property
during the absence of surveillance.
I see.
Well. we'll have to factor
that into our thinking.
I haven't shared this with
anyone else. boss.
Thanks. Kate.
Someone comes from anti-corruption.
you worry they're not going
to be a team player.
I got fed up of nicking coppers.
I'd rather go after the psycho
that murdered Gail.
Cheers. boss.
What have we got?
Based on the claims made
by Officer J.
DCI Davidson ordered the convoy
to attend the armed robbery
on the grounds there was
an urgent threat to the public.
Fair enough.
This is the getaway van that
triggered DCI Davidson's suspicions.
And these are the MIT vehicles
passing through at high speed.
This. according to Officer J.
is the moment Davidson
made her decision.
But that convoy was
going like the clappers.
You'd do well to spot
a pipe band in there.
I agree. sir.
That's why we need more evidence.
But you have an
informant on the team. right?
She's not responded to any of my
efforts to make further contact.
Going to need more. son.
Kate's Davidson's Deputy SIO.
If anyone's got the inside track.
it's her.
I am aware.
No-one's better qualified or better
positioned to act as a Chis
or even a UCO.
I'll give it some thought.
Carry on.
Sir.
PHONE PINGS
FARIDA: Boss. Ma'am.
Pathologist says he died instantly.
The pattern of injuries implies
a fall from height.
OK. have we confirmed ID yet?
I took the liberty of sending
a photo to the handler.
He confirms it's the Chis.
Shit.
Sorry. boss.
Got the file on the Chis -
a low-level offender named
Alastair Oldroyd.
Unfortunately.
there's nothing on CCTV.
so whatever happened to him
happened in a blind spot.
Door-to-door haven't found any
witnesses to the fall.
Right.
A number of people do report
hearing a scream.
Suggests he was pushed.
but not conclusively.
Either way. we've lost the only
person that can say for certain
if Terry Boyle claimed to have been
involved in Gail's murder
or it was someone else.
Yep.
If only we'd have been given his ID.
we might have been able
to have saved him.
Exactly.
Cheers. boss.
Steve Arnott.
SHE SNIFFLES
Farida. are you OK?
What's happened?
Our most important witness was
just found dead.
What witness?
This is too dangerous.
Wait.
You're not suggesting Davidson
was involved?
You have no idea what she's
capable of. none at all.
Don't call me again.
CALL DISCONNECTS
Second MIT interview of Terry Boyle
by DCI Davidson and DS Lomax.
Mr Boyle. you remain under caution.
Please refer to Document 36
submitted in Disclosure.
Document 36 is a report regarding
fingerprints detected
at Flat 4F. Beechwood House
during a lawful search
on 27th October.
A number of said prints match
the fingerprints
obtained from Mr Boyle following
his arrest.
A significant number of other
fingerprints match an individual
identified by the Police National
Computer as Carl Banks.
Terry. what is your relationship
with Carl Banks?
Do you know Carl Banks?
No comment.
You sure that's how you
want to answer?
Can you tell us who is Carl Banks?
I suggest you arrest Mr Banks and
put that question to him.
rather than to my client.
So far we've been unable
to trace Carl Banks.
Perhaps your client
will provide information
that will help us locate him.
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
Document 42 submitted in Disclosure.
For the DIR. Document 42
is a report on chemical traces
detected in Flat B. Dorton Villas
on 28th October.
Said traces have been
identified as cleaning fluids.
Did you carry out a thorough
cleaning of the premises
in order to
destroy forensic evidence?
For the DIR. the suspect
is not responding.
Image 27 submitted for Disclosure.
Image 27 is a crime scene photograph
captured during a lawful search
of Flat B. Dorton Villas
on 28th October
showing the kitchen area.
Markings on the floor suggest
a large appliance
had been present for some time.
Please cross-reference
with Document 42 -
chemical traces detected resembling
refrigerator coolant.
Our assumption is the removal
of a refrigerator or freezer.
What happened to this appliance?
I don't know.
Document 42 again.
Further chemical traces were
detected which have been identified
as two substances listed under
the Misuse of Drugs Act in Class A -
cocaine and diamorphine.
Diamorphine is commonly known
as heroin.
Have you ever used these substances?
Do you have an explanation for why
these substances were detected in
your flat?
No comment.
These are powerful substances.
Even in small quantities.
they can affect mood and memory.
They can cause unpredictable.
violent behaviour.
Images 20 to 22.
Images 20 to 22 are photos
of Gail Vella
found in Flat B. Dorton Villas
during a lawful search
on 28th October.
Document 44 submitted in...
May I interject?
You've presented evidence of intense
cleaning at my client's home.
Why. then. would these incriminating
images have been left behind?
Document 44 submitted in Disclosure.
Document 44 describes
deposits of semen
detected on said images
of Gail Vella.
Analysis of these deposits of semen
gives a 99.9% probability that they
originated from your client.
Did you want to have sexual
relations with Gail Vella?
Did you want her to be
your girlfriend?
For the DIR. the suspect
is not responding.
Did you become angry or frustrated?
Did it make you want to hurt Gail?
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
I'm showing the suspect an image
of an article of clothing. BC-9.
recovered from Flat B. Dorton Villas
on 28th October.
Document 60 submitted in Disclosure.
Document 60 is a report of particles
of gunshot residue
detected on BC-9.
Mr Boyle. did you shoot Gail Vella?
HE GRUNTS
HE GROANS
GROANS INTENSIFY
What kind of knobby signal was that?
First thing that came to mind.
Go round the block in case
anyone's watching.
No worries.
There's a nice little
balti up the road.
but I'm guessing that's not why
you're here. though.
I wish. Sorry. mate.
Right.
I can't share any details.
but we might be looking into Vella.
Oh. shit.
Great. so when Buckells and Davidson
find out. they're going to think...
They'll think either you're our Chis
or you've been embedded as a UCO.
That's why I'm giving you
a heads-up. Kate.
Steve. you know what it's like being
ex-anticorruption. I've had to work
my bollocks off with them lot.
Is this the gaffer's
way of getting his own back?
No. of course not.
Why am I still calling him
"gaffer?!"
He knows why you moved on.
Yeah. that's what worries me.
AC-12 was tainted when the gaffer
got investigated.
Look. you'd done your time. made
DI. You wanted to move on.
He knows it was nothing personal.
Except you stayed.
So. what next? You opening an
official inquiry?
We can keep it on the DL only if
we've got a Chis inside MIT.
Great. So either I'm accused of
being a traitor
or I become one to avoid
being accused?
Jesus Christ. Steve.
I'm going to have to think about it.
Cheers. Kate.
That's all anyone can ask.
The address where Terry Boyle
was arrested
was covered in prints matching
Carl Banks.
One initial line of inquiry in Vella
was a contract killing.
According to my informant
on the Hill.
Operation Lighthouse has detected
forensic evidence
linking to this suspect -
Carl Banks.
Carl Banks has an extensive
history of violence.
including firearms offences.
and a long association
with organised crime.
It's much more likely to be
the gunman than the local oddball.
That's for sure. Yes. sir.
It would appear that DCI Davidson
deliberately delayed
the operation to arrest the suspect.
it's possible this was instrumental
in enabling Banks.
the real killer. to flee.
If we want to get to the truth.
there's no choice. sir -
we've got to start formally
investigating Davidson.
Well. that's what we do. son.
We hunt the truth.
Inquiry authorised.
Thank you. sir.
What are you waiting on.
a puff of white smoke?
Sir.
I thought we agreed you'd be out?
You don't even want to
talk about it?
We've talked enough.
I just want to get
the last of my things.
I don't want a row. Farida.
It's over.
Farida. please.
You moving in with her now?
"Her"?
Smart money's on Kate Fleming.
Kate and I have been shagging
on the sly for months
even though she's straight
and I never cheated on you.
Now I see why you
never made detective.
Don't patronise me!
You think you're so fantastic!
You think you're so powerful!
No. but at work I'm your boss.
and I've still treated you
with respect the whole time
you've destroyed our relationship
with your paranoia.
And out of work. what am I to you?
You still act like we're
just friends.
You're ashamed of me!
No. of course not. How come I've
never met your family?
I don't have one.
You're lying. Everyone has a family.
This is why I'm leaving.
This madness!
I'm sorry. Jo.
SHE SOBS
I'm sorry.
I love you. Jo.
Please don't go.
MUFFLED VOICES
Jo. he made a confession.
It's not good enough. sir.
No. this isn't good enough.
This isn't good enough.
This is your gig. Jo.
Christ sake! I can see you're
frustrated. sir.
Oh. really? Really?!
Thanks for that!
Thanks a million!
We need to consider next steps.
Look. what am I going to tell
the Chief!
I've explained everything
clearly. sir.
Would you like me
to go through it again?
DOOR SLAMS
Boss? You OK?
I just took the Super
through my decision on Terry Boyle.
I've recommended he be put on police
bail pending further inquiries.
I've released him without charge.
Right.
Don't look so surprised. Kate.
I wasn't born yesterday.
The gu...
The gunshot particles aren't enough
without spatter of Gail Vella's
blood or tissues.
And the Chis. Carl Banks.
Terry Boyle's flat -
something doesn't add up.
Yeah. I agree. boss.
I just want to catch the bastard
who killed Gail Vella.
She's what this is all about.
No way am I going after someone
like Terry Boyle
because he's the easy way out.
Boss...
..is everything OK?
Thanks. Kate.
I should. um... Yeah.
The police need to know where you
are at all times.
Your flat's still a crime scene
so they've arranged
for you to stay in what they call
"approved premises."
You'll be safe there. Terry.
Thank you.